## Luiz Gonzaga dos Santos Filho, MBA

💡 Vancouver, Canada 🛮 🏫 www.luiz.dev 🛛 Email 🛗 LinkedIn 🧐 Topmate 🛂 SpeakerDeck 🕠 GitHub

A people-first leader building high-performing teams and scaling organizations for ~22 years.

I'm continually upskilling myself and love sharing what I know. Feel free to check some of my testimonials and recommendations on my LinkedIn and Topmate profiles (where I've been recognized as a top 1% mentor globally and top 100 in Canada).

For a more verbose version of my resumé, visit luiz.dev/cv/verbose.

## Experience

Mentor @ Topmate.io

Oct 2023 – present

Awarded top 1% globally and top 100 in Canada

Software Engineering Manager → Senior Software Engineering Manager @ Coursera

Seb 2021 – present

Drove Enterprise growth: by leading key Enterprise initiatives, unlocking 7 figures of dollars in recurring revenue

Grew the Enterprise org: managed several teams and charters, hired and promoted engineers to Senior, Staff and Manager

Enhanced organizational efficiency with org-wide processes, improving metrics and accountability, reducing touchpoints, improving leadership decision-making and recouping 6 figures of dollars per quarter

Championed DE&I and well-being by authoring and driving different org-wide policies around DE&I, measurably increased our hiring pipeline's diversity and maintained highest team retention in the org

Software Engineering Manager II → Software Engineering Manager III @ Amazon / AWS

(Sep 2017 – Dec 2020

At Amazon Payments: led a cross-functional team to deliver the end-to-end payments integration for Amazon Turkey (amazon.com.tr), involving international and cross-department collaboration and materializing Amazon's expansion in Europe; drove early adoption of PSD2 regulations, ensuring European market compliance ahead of competitors; owned Payment on Delivery for India market

At AWS Route53: hired and grew a team from scratch; measurably improved operational efficiency, accessibility, and usability across five different products; owned multiple product roadmaps and delivered two global product launches, expanding AWS Route53's presence into new markets and

Drove organizational change and fostered inclusion: improved our sourcing efficiency by ~32% and our pipeline's diversity by ~11%; championed an engineering-wide policy to promote inclusion and belonging; as a certified Cultural Competences for Teams instructor, trained hundreds of leaders and engineers around diversity and inclusion

Mentored and supported other managers: served on the Software Engineering Manager Peer Advisory board, providing guidance and support to

Senior Frontend Engineer → Frontend Team Lead @ Brandwatch

( Apr 2016 - Feb 2017

As the Frontend team lead: helped the PM with agile ceremonies and backlog prioritization; liaison with the team manager in the UK headquarters As a Senior Frontend Engineer: worked existing and new feature development on Brandwatch's main product (Analytics); refactored thousands of files on a 5-year-old jQuery codebase, improving bundle size, patching security vulnerabilities, and enabling new features to be used

☐ Full-stack engineer @ X-Team

**(**\sum Apr 2015 – Apr 2015

Short collaboration with X-Team's CTO researching, planning and developing the next phase of X-Labs (their open source initiative) and other internal projects involving IndexedDB

Software Engineering Manager @ DataEasy

**U** Jun 2014 – Mar 2016

Led Engineering Transformation: directed a company-wide shift to modern DevOps and ChatOps practices, including Git, SemVer, CI pipelines, live application monitoring, automated release management, enabling higher quality and faster releases and allowing the IT department to stay leaner

Championed Process Improvement: mapped all engineering processes, reduced touchpoints and staffing needs

Fostered growth and upskilling: partnered with a local university to provide automated testing courses for senior engineers, streamlining testing cycles and reducing release bottlenecks

Cultivated Innovation and Learning: created a bi-weekly program fostering innovation and knowledge sharing through tech talks and experimentation with new technologies

① Apr 2013 – Nov 2013	
Developed their main product line: brand Analytics Wrote codemods to refactor thousands of files, defining conventions for all frontend, reducing code r	eview length and improving time to merge
Senior Frontend Engineer → Frontend Team Lead @ Content Fleet  \( \) Apr 2012 – Mar 2013	
Developed REST APIs and core MVC applications during the startups growth phase Led mobile responsiveness efforts and performance optimization initiatives, significantly reducing ne faster UX, especially on mobile devices Responsible for the frontend strategy, conventions, quality, performance improvements and training	Ç
Full-stack Engineer @ Goiás State Government  Sev 2007 – Mar 2012	
Maintained the State's payroll and other Human Capital Management (HCM) systems for over 200k Led several performance, usability and accessibility improvements	employees and citizens
Junior Full-stack Engineer @ DR Sistemas & Interagi  3 2004 – 2005	
Interagi: developed CRUD applications and did some programmatic image processing DR Sistemas: developed a Backend application for the public law sector	
Misc Software Engineering & Consultancy gigs @ Freelancer  S Jan 2003 – Dec 2014	
Vega Sistemas, Brazil: High-level architecture on migrating a desktop application to a web platform SENAC Goiás, Brazil: Consultancy on web development best practices, productivity tools, agile met their internal development department Federal University of Goiás, Brazil: Developed their public admission (Vestibular) system and websit	
Other	
Over 23 experiences as an instructor or speaker and 7 volunteer positions around leadership, web of	
of them at <u>luiz.dev/cv/verbose</u> .	evelopment, community and the arts. See all
of them at <u>luiz.dev/cv/verbose</u> .  Education	evelopment, community and the arts. See all
	evelopment, community and the arts. See all  Languages
Education	
Education  Degrees  Business Process Management, MBA @ IT Management Institute (IGTI) – Brazil Computer Engineering, Bachelor @ Federal University of Goiás – Brazil	Portuguese — Native English — Fluent
Education  Degrees  Business Process Management, MBA @ IT Management Institute (IGTI) – Brazil Computer Engineering, Bachelor @ Federal University of Goiás – Brazil Computer Science, Visiting Student @ Saint Mary's University – Canada	Portuguese — Native English — Fluent German & Spanish — Basic
Education  Degrees  Business Process Management, MBA @ IT Management Institute (IGTI) – Brazil Computer Engineering, Bachelor @ Federal University of Goiás – Brazil Computer Science, Visiting Student @ Saint Mary's University – Canada  Other  Over 32 courses and specializations taken, 70 books read, 30 events attended and 8 achievements	Portuguese — Native English — Fluent German & Spanish — Basic